<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multi-lingual on </title>
    <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/tags/multi-lingual/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multi-lingual on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bfloeser.netlify.com/tags/multi-lingual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Managing dotfiles with bare git repo</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/tech-tips/dotfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/tech-tips/dotfiles/</guid>
      <description>A tale as old as time: you configure and tweak your personal machine that you use for work, coding, fun and games or whatever and at some point you wonder how you might preserve all those tweaks. Either, you want to back them up (which is always sensible) or you want to transfer to a new machine or want to show them to other people online so they can just download your setup and get going immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Notes</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/tech-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/tech-tips/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with Rust</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/software/rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/software/rust/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I stumbled across some mention of the Stack Overflow Developer Survey which found that the Rust language has held the spot of most loved programming language since 2016. That seemed interesting to me but I didn&amp;rsquo;t follow it up in any way.
A while later I came across some Rust tutorial videos on one of the YouTube channels I frequently visit and looked into it a bit. Looked pretty involved to me and that was that again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/software/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/gaming/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run Gothic 2 on Linux</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/gaming/gothic2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/gaming/gothic2/</guid>
      <description>There are many challenges when it comes to gaming on Linux but it&amp;rsquo;s even more difficult to get something up and running that&amp;rsquo;s so old that it&amp;rsquo;s a hassle to do it under Windows as well.
In essence you have to deal with the setup you&amp;rsquo;d do in Windows (which is already nontrivial) and apply all of it through the layer of abstraction that is running Windows software on Linux. Fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a script on conda activate</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/tech-tips/conda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/tech-tips/conda/</guid>
      <description>I recently noticed that using a conda environment can come with a couple inconveniences. For example, since the default Python executable changes when activating conda, this means that the $PATH variable has been modified and some software can not be found anymore.
For instance, I can&amp;rsquo;t call PyMol from command line when in a conda environment because it somehow depends on the Python executable, it seems.
I recently installed some software into a conda env, that needs a couple of environment variables to run but which I only really need (or want) when running this software in this conda env because it messes with $PATH and disrupts my workflow otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing an Operating System</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/software/os/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/software/os/</guid>
      <description>What? For those who do not know: an operating system (OS) is the software that runs your device, the most popular ones being Windows, MacOS, Android and iOS.
It takes care of communicating with the hardware (that is hard drive, graphics card, processor etc.) and starts it up, provides you with the nice graphical interface that you&amp;rsquo;re (probably) used to and much more. It is also the layer underneath all the applications you&amp;rsquo;re using, like Office, a browser or games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How it all started</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/privacy/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/privacy/start/</guid>
      <description>Back then &amp;hellip; I remember that I used to dismiss privacy-concerned people (of which I knew basically one) as paranoid. I used to be one of the people who asked the rhetorical question of &amp;ldquo;But who would care about my data?&amp;rdquo; followed by &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to hide&amp;rdquo;. This was my point of view some three years ago.
&amp;hellip; and now Fast forward to now:
  I have banned everything Facebook, Google and Microsoft from my household.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Hello world Dear reader, I finally made it! Although I have basically no experience with web development, here is my personal website. I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited about this and it&amp;rsquo;s going to be interesting to see where it takes me. Of course I&amp;rsquo;d like to take all the credit but the truth is that there are software and services out there that make this kind of endeavour relatively easy and painless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bfloeser.netlify.com/posts/privacy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
